Now we're about to jump in and level up our tests.
现在我们要开始升级我们的测试了
But before we do that,
但在此之前
we're going to clean up our Funmi contract a little bit to make it look a little bit more professional.
我们将稍微整理一下 "FundMe" 合约以让它看起来更加专业
And I'm going to talk about some of the syntax and some of the reasons why some conventions exist.
我会讲解一些语法以及一些惯例之所以存在的原因
We're not going to do this full force on all the projects moving forward.
我们不会在之后的项目中往这方面投入很大的力气
But they are good to know and they are good to keep in mind
但了解并记住它们是很有益的
when moving forward and working with our contracts.
尤其是在处理我们的合约的时候
While we go through this we're going to learn why some of these conventions exist
在这个过程中，我们将了解这些惯例为什么会存在
including learning a little bit of low level solidity.
而且会学习一些 Solidity 更底层的知识
So don't skip this part.
因此，请不要跳过这部分
When we get to later sections.
当我们抵达更靠后的章节时
We're going to be a little bit looser and not be as strict with the code style guides
我们会变得稍微宽松一些，不会像代码风格指南那样严格
but That's basically what we're gonna go over now.
但基本上，这就是我们现在要讨论的内容
And for now, you might see this event funded thing here,
现在，你可能会看到这里有个 `event Funded`
please just ignore that for now,
请暂时先忽略它
in an earlier take, I'd introduced the events much earlier.
在较早版本的课程中，我比较早地介绍了 "event"
And now we're actually going to learn about events a little bit later in the course.
但现在我们会在更靠后的课程中学习 "event"
So please ignore that event funded for now.
所以请暂时忽略掉 `event Funded`
So let's go ahead and tweak a little bit of our contracts here.
让我们继续，来稍微修改一下我们的合约
Now what I'm talking about tweaking this to make it look professional, a little bit more professional,
我所说的优化我们的合约以让它看起来更专业的意思
I'm talking about the solidity style guide,
指的就是 Solidity 的风格指南("Style Guide")
there are some conventions for naming and ordering
有一些关于命名和排序的惯例
that we can follow to make our code look a little bit better.
可以通过遵循它们以使我们的代码看起来更好
Now, like I said, this is going to be a little bit more optional,
就像我说的，这是一个可选步骤
because it can be a little bit verbose.
因为它可能会有些冗长
And it doesn't really make that big of a difference.
而且它也不会带来特别大的差异
But it can increase readability of your contracts by a lot and make your code look a lot nicer.
但它可以大大提高合约的可读性并让你的代码更好看
So if you want, you can go through this style guide to learn more about
因此，如果你想的话，可以通过阅读这个风格指南
what kind of makes solidity look nice, and what makes it not look nice.
来了解更多有关哪些做法会让 Solidity 看起来更好，而哪些不会
But well, that's some of these style guides in here,
但这里我们只是介绍一些风格指南
we're not going to follow the style guide exactly to a tee.
并不会严格遵循风格指南的每一处细节
But we are going to make some best efforts to make our code follow the style guide,
不过我们还是会尽力让我们的代码遵循风格指南
we've got a link to the style guide in the GitHub repository for this section,
我们在 GitHub 仓库的这一部分提供了风格指南的链接
we can read some more about the layout.
我们可以读到许多关于布局的内容
But the main thing we want to look at is this order of the layout,
但我们主要看的是布局的顺序
we want to start with our imports with our pragma statement, our imports, interfaces, libraries, and then contracts.
我们要从版本声明开始("Pragma statement")，然后是导入("Import")、接口(Interfaces)、库(Libraries)、然后是合约(Contracts)
And then inside each contract
接着在合约内部，我们按照
type declarations, state variables, events, modifiers, and functions.
类型声明(Type declarations)、状态变量(State variables)、事件(Events)、修饰器(Modifiers)、以及函数(Function)的顺序编写
So let's go back here and make sure that we're up to speed,
让我们回到这里，确保可以跟上进度
we want our pragma first.
首先是编译器版本声明
Alright, awesome, we did exactly that,
很好，我们已经是这样做的了
then we want our imports. Okay, awesome, we have those too.
接着是导入，很好，我们有这两个
Something that's not in the style guide is going to be error codes,
样式指南中没有提到报错代码(Error Codes)
which we definitely want next.
我们要把它放在下一个位置
So next is going to be error codes.
所以下一个就是报错代码
Now this is where we're going to bump into one of our first updates here.
这里是我们遇到的第一处更新
As of recent, it's sort of becoming a best practice to
最近，有一种写法已经逐渐成为主流
add the name of your contract, some underscores, and then the name of your error.
即，添加你的合约名称，一些下划线，然后是你错误类型的名称
Whenever you're running into an error.
这样每当你遇到报错时
This makes it a lot easier to understand which contract is throwing the error.
都可以更容易地理解是哪个合约引发了错误
So for this, we're going to say error Funmi, two underscores not owner,
具体来说，我们要这么写 `error FundMe__NotOwner`
then we're going to scroll down to the our revert and set it like this.
然后我们拉到下面找到 `revert` 语句，并设置成这样
This way, when if we ever run into this error,
这样的话，只要我们遇到这个报错
we know that the error is coming from the Funmi contract,
就能知道报错来源于 "FundMe" 合约
not from the aggregator v3 interface,
而不是 "AggregatorV3Interface"
or the price converter or some other contract.
或是 "PriceConverter" 又或者其它合约
So that's how we want to write our error codes here.
这就是我们编写报错代码的方式
If we had any interfaces or libraries not imported, we would add them here.
如果我们有任何未导入的接口或库，都会在这里添加
But then finally, we add our contracts.
接着在最后，添加我们的合约
In this file, we only have one contract here.
在这个文件中，我们只有一个合约
It's our Funmi contract. Awesome.
就是我们的 "FundMe" 合约，很好
Now the next thing we want to learn about as far as style guides go is this thing called natspec.
现在，我们要学习的下一个有关风格指南的内容是 "NatSpec"
natspec stands for Etherium natural language specification format.
"NatSpec" 表示以太坊自然语言规范格式("Ethereum Natural Language Specification Format")
And it's basically a way of documenting our code inspired by Doxygen
它是一种受到 "Doxygen" 启发的一种文档化代码的方式
uses Doxygen style comments and tags to help document our code,
它使用 "Doxygen" 风格的注释和标签来帮助文档化我们的代码
you can click the link here in the solidity documentation to learn more about Doxygen.
你可以点击 Solidity 文档这里的链接来了解更多有关 "Doxygen" 的内容
If we scroll down in the documentation, here,
如果我们把文档往下拉
we can see an example of using natspec.
就可以看到一个使用 "NatSpec" 的示例
Whenever we have a contract or a function that needs documentation,
每当我们有需要文档化的合约或函数时
we can add some syntax that looks like this to it.
就可以添加类似这样的语法
So for example, if we wanted to add this to our code,
举个例子，如果要在我们的代码中添加的话
we could add a comment explaining this funding contract
我们可以添加一个注释来解释一下这个 "FundMe" 合约
to start a piece of natspec, you can do three backslashes,
要开始一个 "NatSpec" 部分，你可以使用三个 "/" (反斜杠)
or one backslash, two stars, and then another ending star here.
或一个 "/"，两个 "*" (星号)，以及另外一个用于结尾的 "*"
Everything we put inside of this comment section basically gets turned into a comment.
所有我们放进这个注释部分的内容都属于注释
For the start of our contract, we'll do the Add sign title
对于合约的开头，我们将添加标记 `@title`
to explain basically, what this contract is,
基本上就是在解释，这是个什么合约
it's fun, we contract is going to be a contract for crowdfunding,
对于我们的 "FundMe" 合约，它是“一个用于众筹的合约”
("A contract for crowd funding")
we'll add another star. And we can add the author of it,
再加一个 "*"，我们可以添加它的“作者”("author")
which is going to be your name, I'm going to put Patrick Collins, of course,
也就是你的名字，而我要写的是 "Patrick Collins"，这是当然了
then we'll add a notice, which is just kind of a note to people
接着我们添加一个“注意”("notice")，就是用来提示他人的
we can say this contract is is to demo a sample funding contract.
我们可以说“该合约是一个众筹合约的示例”
("This contract is to demo a sample funding contracts")
And we can also add apt Dev,
我们还可以添加 `@dev`
which is a note specifically to developers.
这是一个专门针对开发者的说明
And we can say this implements price feeds as our library.
我们可以说“该合约使用了喂价的库实现”
("This implements price feeds as out library")
The reason that we want to add these tags here
我们之所以在这里添加这些标签
is actually because we can use the natspec to automatically create documentation for us
是因为我们可以使用 "NatSpec" 来自动为我们创建文档
if we download so we can actually run solc dash s user doc dash dash dev doc,
如果我们下载了 "solc" 则可以运行 `solc --userdoc --devdoc`
and the name of our file to automatically generate documentation.
以及我们想要的文件名称，来自动生成文档
So this is also really helpful for automatically creating documentation for other developers who interact with the protocol later on.
因此，这对于以后要进行协议交互的其他开发人员生成文档也很有帮助
You can use this natspec For as many or as few functions as you'd like.
你可以根据需要尽可能或多或少的用一点这个 "NatSpec" 的功能
Most of us probably aren't going to be making documentation.
我们中的大多数人可能并不会去编写文档
So we really just want to follow those guidelines
所以我们只需要遵守这个指南
if we think some function or some section of our code is a little bit tricky for other developers.
如果我们认为某些函数或部分的代码对其他开发者来说比较棘手的话
Now that we're inside of contract,
现在我们到了合约内部
we can follow the order of our contract.
可以按照这个顺序来进行
We're first going to start with type declarations
我们首先要从，“类型声明”("Type Declarations")开始
which we don't really have any except for the fact
我们其实没有任何类型声明
that we're using our price converter for the UN 256 type.
除了这个 `PriceConverter for uint256`
Okay, great. You Next, after our type declarations,
很好，下一个，在 "Type declarations" 之后
we're going to do state variables.
我们要处理“状态变量”("State variables")
And in this state variables section,
在这个状态变量部分
this is where we're actually going to change the name of some of our state variables.
我们需要更改一些状态变量的名称
So we'll do a little common here state variables.
我们在这里做一个注释 "State Variables!"
Now in the solidity style guide, kind of adhere to the naming styles,
在 Solidity 风格指南中，我们要遵循它的命名风格
we use upper and lowercase,
我们要使用大小写混合
we use total caps with underscores here.
带有下划线的要全部大写
However, these naming variables are going to change in the future in this section.
然而，这个部分的这些变量的命名将来会发生改变
And if you're following along with the GitHub repo associated with this course,
如果你正在关注本课程关联的 GitHub 仓库
these are going to be actually a little bit different than what you see.
就会发现那里和你现在看到的有些不同
However, for now, we're going to leave them as they are,
但现在，我们暂时保持原样
because the reason why we're going to change them isn't going to be quite clear yet.
因为我们还不是很清楚要更改它们的原因
Don't worry. So these names are going to change soon, but not yet.
别着急，这些名称很快就会更改，但不是现在
Alright, after state variables comes events, and modifiers.
好的，在状态变量之后是“事件”("Events")和“修饰器”("Modifiers")
We don't have any events, but we do have a modifier.
我们没有任何事件但有一个修饰器
So we'll copy this. And actually, we'll delete this comment here.
所以我们要复制它，然后删除这里的注释
And we'll paste our modifier here.
接着把我们的修饰器粘贴到这里
Oh, and it looks like looks like we're not auto formatting here.
哦，看起来这里没有被自动格式化
So we're going to uncomment immutable actually,
我们把这里的 "immutable" 解除注释
so that it automatically auto formats.
这样它就会进行自动格式化
Okay, great. We're out of formatting now. And Cool.
很好，现在已经是格式化的了，酷~
Alright, so now we have our modifiers. Next,
好的，现在我们已经处理好了修饰器，下一个
we have right here, and then we have all of our functions. Great.
我们现在位于这里，接下来要处理我们所有的函数，很好
We actually want to group our functions in this order that I just print here.
我们打算按照这个顺序来对我们的函数进行分组，我已经打在这里了
So we want the constructor which we have
先是“构造函数”("constructor")，我们有
received and fall back, we do have fall back and receive.
然后是 "receive" 和 "fallback"，我们也确实有 "fallback" 和 "receive"
So we're going to actually copy those and delete this comment.
所以我们要把它们复制下来，删掉这里的注释
We're gonna stick those veterans Heath here looks like receive goes first. So we'll put that here.
把它们粘贴到这里来，看起来 "receive" 要放在前面，把它放到这里
Then external functions, then public, internal, private.
接下来是 "external" 函数，再接下来是 "public", "internal", "private"
So we have public public. And that's it. And then we can delete this part down here. Okay. Cool.
我们有 "public", "public" 就是这样，然后删除下面这部分，很好，酷~
And if we want, we can do that syntax up here from the net spec for our functions.
如果我们愿意，可以对我们的函数使用 "NatSpec" 的语法
For example, for fund it, we could even just copy paste,
举个例子，对于 "fund()"，我们可以直接复制粘贴
we would remove title, we would remove author,
删除 "title"，删除 "author"
and we just say add, notice, this function, funds this contract.
只需要保留 "notice"，“该函数为本合约吸纳资金”
("This function funds this contract")
And we can even leave a little dev thing here to talk about it.
我们也可以保留一个 "dev" 内容做点说明
Now if we have parameters, you can do apt puram.
如果我们有一些参数，你可以添加 "@param"
And say like what the parameter is.
并描述相应的参数
And then if we have returns, we can say returns,
如果有返回值，则可以添加 "@return"
or returns and then what it returns for the documentation.
来说明返回值是什么
Since this doesn't have any parameters in here, and doesn't return anything,
因为它这里并没有任何参数，也不返回任何内容
we can just leave it like this.
所以我们可以就保持这样
And great, we've just revamped our contract here to make it a little bit more nicely formatted. Great job.
很好，我们已经重新整理了我们的合约，并使其格式更加整洁，干得好
Now, like I said,
正如我所说的
we actually are going to change the names of our state variables,
我们实际上还要更改状态变量的名称
and we're going to add some functions in here and a little bit.
并在这里添加一些函数
So if we're following with the GitHub repo,
如果你正在关注 GitHub 仓库
the state of the contract right now is going to look a little bit different.
会发现合约的状态会与这里看到的有些不同
But it'll make sense why change this up in a little bit.
稍后我们会解释为什么要做出这些改变